Where to begin?
With water?
Or with fire?
Whoa, boy. Whoa.
Come on, Old Boy.
Want some?
Squirrel, where did you get that?
Found it.
Bit strong.
But not bad.
Witch.
Piss off, half-wit!
Are you heading to the pyre?
I wish I could go.
Gods, I forgot the offering.
Mother will kill me.
Save them.
Death is not the end,
Fey Queen.
Seek him.
Death is not the end.
Save them.
I don't understand.
Save who?
No!
What did you do?
What do you think, fool?
Shot supper.
Don't get too close to this witch,
you'll get the worms.
Even her dad left her.
Papa, please!
Papa, don't go! Come back!
Left his own clan
'cause she scared him off.
You are cursed, Nimue.
What did you say?
Don't get brave with me, hag.
Get out of my forest.
I'm not afraid of you...
Get out of my forest!
Get it off me!
Pull it off!
Stop.
Help!
It's in your blood, child.
Let him go!
Quick!
- I got you.
- Nimue.
Stop!
Help!
Nimue!
Nimue.
- Help!
- Let him go.
She brings darkness in the house!
Papa, don't go!
We're cursed.
Benum.
What happened?
She did it! She did it!
She did it!
Cast her out!
- You will string Benum a new bow.
- It wasn't my fault. It just happened.
I'm sorry, Mother.
I couldn't control it.
He will live,
you will make an offering to the family,
I will explain to the Elders.
- I want it to stop. Why won't it stop?
- It will not stop.
No, I hate it!
- It's right what they say about me.
- No.
Never be ashamed of what you are.
They don't call you "demon."
Or "witch."
Did I raise you to suffer fools
or to lead?
Help them understand.
No Sky Folk has ever wielded such power.
Some of us can hear the Hidden...
Are you the High Priestess now
or my mother?
We will discuss this later.
I don't want to go.
You are my daughter and apprentice,
and you will make your offering.
As Summoner,
Agatha communed with the Hidden...
safeguarded our harvest...
and divined the winds.
Let Airimid's Breath push her down
the Great River to the Other World,
where her voice will join
the chorus of our ancestors.
As Sky Folk,
we are born in the dawn...
- to pass in the twilight.
- To pass in the twilight.
The Hidden are with us.
They choose the new Summoner.
Not her. No.
No.
No, not her.
- She is marked by Dark Gods.
- Not her!
- It's witchcraft.
- Sorcery.
How dare you?
The Hidden have chosen.
Nimue is the new Summoner.
I don't want it.
I don't want to be your Summoner!
Nimue.
Nimue!
- Nimue!
- Did you enjoy that?
It's not a question of what you want
or what I want.
The will of the Hidden is clear.
The power is a gift and should be used
to guide and serve your kind.
A gift?
It's a curse.
And I don't want to be like you.
And it is very clear
what my kind think of me.
I wonder why.
You do everything in your power
to prove them right.
Nimue.
Well, I relieve you forever
of this burden.
Nimue!
We saw the eclipse.
What's happened?
I'm Summoner.
You're what?
It doesn't matter.
I'm going.
I'm getting on that ship today.
It's still in Hawksbridge.
What? Nimue, slow down,
you're not making any sense.
They don't want me here,
and I don't want them.
- They can all burn in the nine hells.
- Who? What, the Elders?
Who cares
what those shriveled onions think?
Nimue.
You're not really going.
Pym, I have to.
Oh, my gods,
you're acting mad.
I'm riding with you.
God is love.
It is a love that purifies,
sanctifies, and unites us.
And today,
God smiles.
Do you know why?
Because we've done his
work today.
You see,
God created most of us
in his image.
This is his garden,
and we must tend his garden.
We must rake the garden
and pull the weeds.
The weeds are the demons,
and we must expel them
from his garden.
Do you understand?
But the demons wear many faces.
They don't want to be found.
Some of their faces are scary ones.
Some are shy.
And some...
are very young.
We do his work today.
Lenore!
It's a Moon Wing.
They came by day as we slept.
The men in red robes.
They burned our trees.
The smoke killed many in their sleep.
Others burned...
or fell.
The rest fell
to the steel of the Gray Monk.
The one who cries.
The Red Paladins are moving north.
And we're right in their path.
We need to send scouts
to get a sense of their numbers.
Will the king do nothing
about this slaughter?
We are on our own.
No friends of the Fey
serve Uther Pendragon.
Yeah.
I hate wizards.
If he so much as points a finger at me,
you stick him, Hook.
Merlin the Magician?
You owe Lord Gray River
4,000 gold coin.
Oi!
Bloody hell.
Search his robes.
A Carpathian king once sent 400 assassins
to claim my head.
Dacians.
I burned them all in a lightning storm
that lasted seven whole days.
Tell Lord Gray River
I'm insulted by this paltry show of force.
Or better yet,
I'll send you back as mole rats...
to convey my displeasure?
The spell is quite simple.
Chiggur...
No, no, no, no.
No. It...
There's no call for that type of thing,
Lord Merlin. But just...
Hook.
We're just...
Let's go.
But you didn't turn them into mole rats,
did you, Merlin?
Maybe the rumors are true, then.
Maybe you really have
lost your magic.
At least two dozen Fey villages
have burned at the torch of Father Carden
and the Red Paladins, Your Majesty.
This Carden has his bloody nerve.
Not only nerve,
but popular support.
Given the months of drought and famine,
the peasantry now assign most of the blame
for their miseries to Fey witchcraft.
"Most of the blame"?
Well, the rest blame you, sire.
For the drought?
They blame us?
Merlin.
Perfect timing.
That is debatable,
Your Majesty.
We found him in the cabbages,
sire. Drunk, I'm afraid.
Shocking.
You promised us rain, Merlin.
You promise many things,
and they never seem to happen.
Weather is fickle, my liege.
A classic Merlin answer.
You see, Borley,
Merlin is a conflicted creature.
These are his kind being
put to the torch.
Yet...
he seems rather unmoved.
Well, the Fey Kind are, quite frankly,
better farmers.
So, in times of want,
the mob finds reason to
steal their food.
Father Carden and his paladins
are dull vessels for these old hatreds,
and nothing more.
However,
if His Majesty would allow it,
the Shadow Lords may be able
to offer some service here.
Shadow Lords?
It's a bit late for your enchanters
to help us now.
Not necessarily.
They can pull certain strings
to slow Carden's march.
There are Shadow Lords
at every level of socie...
We want rain, Merlin!
To hell with your Shadow Lords.
I will redouble my efforts,
Your Majesty.
Yes, do.
I can't believe you dragged me here.
I've got lye smell all over me.
No one asked you to come.
Well, you don't know what you're doing.
I do know.
Gawain took the Brass Shield,
the only ship that crosses the sea
to the desert kingdoms.
Because nobody wants to go
to the desert kingdoms,
- which should tell you something.
- I'm getting on it.
Nimue, the Hidden chose you.
We all saw the eclipse.
That means you're Summoner.
And it makes sense,
with what you can do.
You sound like Mother.
At least your mother wants you home.
Mine wants me out.
And this will be her excuse. She'll say,
"Nimue's gone, get on with it."
- She'll marry me off to the fishmonger.
- Stinky Aaron.
It's not funny.
It's kind of funny.
What if they find out you're a girl?
I'm cutting my hair.
But what if they find out
you're Fey Kind?
They won't.
You'll look after Old Boy?
No, I'll let him starve.
What about money?
- I have 20 silver.
- Well, what if they rob you?
Pym!
Look,
I don't even see the ship.
- All right? You've made your point.
- No.
It was supposed to be here.
Stop it.
Stop. Stop it.
Excuse me, sir.
- When is the Brass Shield due to arrive?
- She's not going.
Brass Shield left yesterday.
But it... It's not supposed to leave
for another week.
Tell that to the easterly winds.
Well, when does it return?
Six months.
Now, do you mind?
Oi!
Those can't stay there.
You guys are not shifting this
fast enough.
At least I get to keep you
a bit longer.
Hmm?
Six months.
I know.
I'll be Summoner,
and you marry Stinky Aaron.
Hmm?
Come on,
your life's not so horrible.
Come on.
Out from in there,
you little tyke!
Would you like to buy some of my pies?
Fresh. Just made this very morning.
Sorry!
I'm hungry.
Oh, sheep.
Look. Isn't that amazing?
Wow. Look there.
Ooh, look.
This is your color.
What do you think about this? I like this.
That doesn't work.
Come on, Nimue.
There's music.
♪ With meadows green and skies a-blue ♪
♪ My mistress struck her arrow true ♪
♪ We kissed and danced
'Neath Virgo's eye ♪
♪ As the waxing moon fled from July ♪
♪ Sing high-lolly-lo
Say my fair summer lady ♪
♪ Sing high-lolly-li-summer-hi-lolly-lo ♪
♪ But autumn gusts do blow cold
Summer lady ♪
♪ The swallows fly south from
their nests In the bailey ♪
♪ And the warm,
warm wine ♪
♪ But along came a maid ♪
♪ With eyes like
the ice on the sea ♪
♪ Sing high-lolly-lo
Say my fair winter lady ♪
He fancies you.
Stop it.
Look at that!
You dropped this, milady.
Do I look like a juggler to you?
Not quite yet, no.
Perfect.
I only juggle fire.
Oh, I believe that.
Fancy an ale?
We don't drink with strange men.
What's your name?
I'm Nimue.
- This is Pym.
- Hello.
Well, now we're not strangers.
I'm Arthur.
It's late.
We should go. As it is,
we'll be riding in the dark. Come on.
Then no point worrying about it,
is there?
So...
you're not from Hawksbridge.
Where are you from?
Near enough.
And you?
We both know
you're not a professional singer.
That hurts.
Are you a sword for hire?
A knight, milady.
What? You don't believe me?
Uh, you just seem a bit young and scruffy
for a knight.
Lads, Arthur's found himself
some nice country girls.
Look at that fine skin.
- Do you girls dance?
- Carry on.
Ah-ah-ah!
May I have a go?
- No. Bad idea.
- What are you doing?
But of course, milady.
You got five silver?
I don't, I'm afraid.
Well...
we allow different wagers.
- How about we roll for a kiss?
- Oh, we were just leaving, actually.
Fine.
But if I win,
I get ten silver.
- You can't win. The dice are weighted.
- Shut your mouth.
Ten? To me...
high price indeed.
Just roll seven in any combination.
Three and four, five and two. See?
The odds favor you.
I've just had a rush of dumb luck.
Roll them again.
Why? I won.
Best two out of three.
Seems fair.
Those weren't the rules.
Roll again. Don't be daft.
Then it's 20 silver if I win.
Can you believe this little maid, eh?
You want 20 silver?
Then I want my money's worth as well.
- Deal.
- Nimue, enough.
You witching me?
Why?
Are you afraid of witches?
Nimue, come on!
Who the hell is she?
Witch!
Stop the witch!
Oops, sorry!
You! You! Girls!
- Oi, stop!
- Witches!
- I said, stop!
- Out of the way!
Dellum the Physician?
Who's asking?
I've heard you're a collector of sorts.
No, you misheard.
I was told to stop doing that,
so everything here is quite above board.
- Sanctioned and all that.
- Pity.
See, I was willing to pay handsomely
for a chance to see
your even more obscure items.
Well, is there anything in particular
you're looking for?
I'm looking for the number three.
You're him, ain't you?
There's mad rumors you work for the king.
- You're Merlin...
- Shh!
Bad things happen
to those who speak my name aloud.
- Do you have what I'm looking for?
- The number three, yes.
I acquired it three days ago,
as a matter of fact.
Born to a peasant family in Shorne.
Don't mind the smell.
Oh, allow me.
That'll do.
Uh, m-might I inquire
as to the interest in this item?
Three faces, nine doves, 31 magpies,
three-one-one-three, 13.
Magical child.
A new dawn and
a great and terrible war.
Thanks...
No.
Who are they?
I don't know.
We have to go faster.
What are you doing?
We can't outrun them.
Shh.
Shh shh-shh shh.
- There.
- Right.
Ya! Go on!
By the way,
you dropped this.
You came all this way
just to return a cloak?
And to see you got home safely.
Sorry about the tavern.
You mean your friends, the knights?
- I'm not like Bors.
- What, you're not a mercenary?
I think what she means to say,
though she's clearly mentally incapable
at the moment,
is, "Thank you,
that's very nice of you."
You're Fey, aren't you?
I haven't met your kind before.
You don't seem so scary.
Well, that's because
you don't know us very well.
- Witching men in broad daylight.
- We're not witches.
Bors is one thing,
Red Paladins are quite another.
They're burning Fey villages
along the Beggar's Coast.
So, you need to be careful.
Hey, where are you going?
Making camp.
There's a lot of paladins on the road.
I've got fire and good wine.
Well, the wine's awful,
but the company's good.
Any objections?
What are you doing?
Stalking.
Have you held a sword before?
I've killed hundreds.
I think I can get closer.
Be careful.
- To the death, is it?
- If you're careless.
You're just using the blade.
That's a waste of a good sword.
You talk too much.
A sword is more than a blade.
It's the cross guard.
It's the pommel.
Legs.
Body weight.
- Head.
- Tavern brawler, eh?
Yah!
Ow.
Yield.
You cheated.
Did I hurt you?
You've lowered your guard.
Your sword is in the grass.
- I won.
- Have you?
Is that a cheese knife?
- Yield.
- To you?
Gladly.
Nimue!
Pym.
Pym, we have to go.
- My head.
- Shh. Shh!
It's the wine.
Come on.
Hey. Don't wake him.
Go on then. Tell me what happened.
No. Nothing.
Oh, come on.
Did you kiss him? Did he kiss you?
No.
Why not?
He's gorgeous.
Can we just not talk about this?
No, we're definitely talking about it.
Does he have onion breath
or something?
No, I had a vision.
All right?
Was it the real deal?
Your eyes rolled back and everything?
I don't know.
Gods, we've been gone
for nearly two days.
Nimue.
Mother.
- Mother!
- Nimue, no!
- Pym!
- Nimue!
- Nimue! Help me!
- Pym.
Help me! No!
Pym!
No!
- Come here.
- No!
No!
No.
Come with me.
In here.
Are you hurt?
I can't find Papa.
Squirrel, listen to me.
Go to the Iron Wood
and hide in the Old Man Rock.
Do you understand?
Hey, are you listening?
Run like you do in our fox races.
No one can ever catch you.
You'll come for me?
Yeah, I will. I will.
I need to find Pym and Mother first.
I saw your mother near the temple.
They were chasing her.
You'll be faster without it.
Fast as the fox.
Go.
See this, brothers?
This is why we must be strong.
He will take forms...
that will tear our hearts.
Look at her.
Such eyes.
Yet infected just the same.
We should give thanks, my brothers,
for this opportunity to show our resolve
in the face of such treachery.
Now give her to the fire.
Reveal its true form.
No... no!
No.
Fey archers to the north!
Stop!
You! After her!
Mother?
- No.
- Nimue.
- I'm sorry.
- Nimue, listen.
- I shouldn't have gone.
- Nimue.
I shouldn't have gone!
- I... No, don't.
- Listen to me.
Listen to me.
There is something...
There is something you must do.
Take this to Merlin.
But we have to run.
We have to run.
No. This is your charge.
It's all that matters now.
Bring this to Merlin.
Run, Nimue.
- No...
- Run.
No. No,
I won't leave you. No!
- No!
- I love you more than anything.
Mother.
No!
Go!
Run!
Hold the rod.
Are we...
are we sure it's safe up here, sir?
Take it outside.
Outside?
Outside!
Is that a good idea?
Hold it up!
Aim it at the clouds!
Feet on the metal!
Why? What's gonna happen?
This is madness!
- Wait.
- No, please.
Oh, gods.
The heavens have opened, my friends.
Rejoice!
The drought is ended.
- To the king!
- Uther!
We do not drink to the rain.
We drink it.
- Hail...
- Hail Uther!
What?
What is this?
What trick is this?
That is the rain
that fell upon the castle.
Merlin.
Merlin!
No!
Fight, Nimue.